<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://phiresky.github.io/blog/</id>
    <title>phiresky's blog</title>
    <updated>2019-12-14T11:02:13.846Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <subtitle>About my personal projects and other stuff</subtitle>
    <rights>yup</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating a blog]]></title>
        <id>https://phiresky.github.io/blog/2019/about</id>
        <link href="https://phiresky.github.io/blog/2019/about"/>
        <updated>2019-06-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World! I finally decided to make a blog to put my ramblings and projects. After some deliberation I settled on using next.js, so I can use React+TypeScript, don’t need a server and the website is accessible without JS enabled. The content is written as markdown, though I’m adding some neat...]]></summary>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automatic citation extraction from URLs (draft)]]></title>
        <id>https://phiresky.github.io/blog/2019/pandoc-url2cite</id>
        <link href="https://phiresky.github.io/blog/2019/pandoc-url2cite"/>
        <updated>2019-12-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[pandoc-url2cite[1] allows you to instantly and transparently cite most papers directly given only a single URL. You simply add a URL of a publication, and it will replace that with a real citation in whatever CSL[2] style you want. This means you can avoid dealing with Mendeley[3] or Zotero[4] and...]]></summary>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[rga: ripgrep, but also search in PDFs, E-Books, Office documents, zip, tar.gz, etc.]]></title>
        <id>https://phiresky.github.io/blog/2019/rga--ripgrep-for-zip-targz-docx-odt-epub-jpg</id>
        <link href="https://phiresky.github.io/blog/2019/rga--ripgrep-for-zip-targz-docx-odt-epub-jpg"/>
        <updated>2019-06-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[rga is a line-oriented search tool that allows you to look for a regex in a multitude of file types. rga wraps the awesome ripgrep and enables it to search in pdf, docx, sqlite, jpg, zip, tar.*, movie subtitles (mkv, mp4), etc. github repo Linux build status Crates.io fearless...]]></summary>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pandoc Test Suite]]></title>
        <id>https://phiresky.github.io/blog/2019/writer</id>
        <link href="https://phiresky.github.io/blog/2019/writer"/>
        <updated>2006-07-16T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a set of tests for pandoc. Most of them are adapted from John Gruber’s markdown test suite.HeadersLevel 2 with an embedded linkLevel 3 with emphasisLevel 4Level 5Level 1Level 2 with emphasisLevel 3 with no blank lineLevel 2 with no blank lineParagraphs Here’s a regular paragraph. In...]]></summary>
    </entry>
</feed>